if you're an Android developer then
如果您是Android开发人员，那么
you've probably seen your fair share of
您可能已经看到了您的合理份额
unusual stack traces and encounter one
不寻常的堆栈痕迹，遇到一个
of these is bad enough as it is without
这些已经足够了，因为没有
having to figure out where it fits
必须弄清楚适合的地方
inside your project and how to go about
项目内部以及如何进行
debugging in in Android studio and
在Android Studio中调试
IntelliJ IDEA there's a handy tool
IntelliJ IDEA有一个方便的工具
called stack base analyzer which by
称为堆栈基础分析器
default will allow you to copy a stack
默认将允许您复制堆栈
trace onto your system clipboard and
跟踪到系统剪贴板上
then switch back to the IDE and it'll
然后切换回IDE，它将
automatically analyze that stack trace
自动分析该堆栈跟踪
for you giving you the ability to
为您提供能力
navigate directly to the source of that
直接导航到该来源
exception and go through the entire
例外，并贯穿整个
stack trace line by line and you can
逐行堆叠跟踪，您可以
also bring this tool up by going on
继续进行此工具
analyze and selecting analyze stack
分析并选择分析堆栈
trace in this video I want to take a
追踪这部影片，我想
look at obfuscation and the obfuscating
看混淆和混淆
scrambled stack traces which here I have
我在这里有混乱的堆栈跟踪
a third-party plugin installed called
安装了名为
the ProGuard unscrambler plugin and
ProGuard解密器插件和
together with the mapping file from the
以及来自
log it will be able to reconstruct your
记录它将能够重建您的
original stack trace from an obfuscated
来自混淆的原始堆栈跟踪
application android uses a tool called
android应用程序使用一个称为
ProGuard to obfuscate your code and what
ProGuard混淆您的代码以及什么
happens when you use ProGuard is it will
当您使用ProGuard时会发生
remove any identifiers z' inside the
删除内部的所有标识符z'
code so all of the packages class names
代码，以便所有包类名
and method names anything will help
和方法名称会有所帮助
someone to reconstruct your original
有人来重建你的原始
source code will be removed it'll try to
源代码将被删除，它将尝试
scramble the source code and in addition
乱码源代码，此外
this will make it more difficult to go
这将使它走起来更加困难
back from a stack trace to your source
从堆栈跟踪返回到源
code but if we do this carefully we'll
代码，但如果我们认真执行此操作，
be able to both obfuscate our code and
既可以混淆我们的代码，又可以
debug any future stack traces that we
调试我们将来的所有堆栈跟踪
may receive from our users now one of
可能会从我们的用户那里收到
the last steps before releasing your
释放您的最后一步
Android application to the world is to
Android应用程序走向世界
enable obfuscation through ProGuard and
通过ProGuard和启用混淆
not only will this strip any identifiers
这不仅会剥离任何标识符
from your code they'll also perform a
从您的代码中，他们还将执行
minification which will optimize your
缩小将优化您的
code and remove any potential unused
代码并删除任何潜在的未使用
resources
资源
and so inside of our modules
在模块内部
build.gradle file you'll find
您将找到的build.gradle文件
configuration for a release build and
发布版本的配置和
here instead of enabling this in the
而不是在这里启用
release build what we'll do is just
发布构建我们要做的只是
duplicate this inside of our own debug
在我们自己的调试中复制此内容
configuration so we'll pretend that
配置，所以我们假装
we're releasing this without actually
我们实际上没有发布这个
signing the whole thing and going
签名整个过程
through all of this adapts if we set
通过所有这些适应如果我们设置
this to true then this will enable
这是真的然后这将启用
ProGuard and we'll have to point it to
ProGuard，我们必须将其指向
any ProGuard configuration files here
此处的所有ProGuard配置文件
you'll find the ProGuard rules for this
您会为此找到ProGuard规则
build and you can add more rules there's
构建，您可以添加更多规则
a whole bunch of documentation and rules
一堆文件和规则
for ProGuard to configure how it
用于ProGuard进行配置
performs the obfuscation process
执行混淆过程
so now let's sink this Gradle project
现在让我们沉没这个Gradle项目
and see what happens when we introduce a
看看当我们引入一个
new exception inside of our code so I'm
我们代码中的新异常，所以我
going to do it's going to open up this
要去做这件事
file and I'm just going to throw an
文件，我只是要扔一个
exception manually I'm going to do one
手动例外，我要去做一个
more thing and add few rules to ProGuard
多做些事情，并为ProGuard添加一些规则
tell it to preserve the line number
告诉它保留行号
table and just go ahead and run this
表，然后继续运行
application now it'll deploy this
应用程序现在将部署
artifact to my emulator and we'll
人工仿真器，我们将
connect to it through DDMS to view the
通过DDMS连接到它以查看
log and you'll see that this
登录，您会看到
nullpointerexception we've added has
我们添加的nullpointerexception有
just been thrown so we can copy this as
刚刚被抛出，所以我们可以将其复制为
plain text now if we go to analyze stack
现在，如果我们要分析堆栈的纯文本
trace it will paste that from our
跟踪它将粘贴我们的
systems clipboard and we can use the
系统剪贴板，我们可以使用
unscrambler together with the mapping
解密器和映射
file that ProGuard generated find this
ProGuard生成的文件找到此文件
under your module under the build
在您的模块下
outputs mapping directory you can just
您可以输出输出映射目录
select that now you can go ahead and
选择，现在您可以继续
analyze the stack trace now those lines
现在分析堆栈跟踪那些行
from our obfuscated stack trace are
从我们混淆后的堆栈跟踪中
reconstructed with the fully qualified
完全合格的重建
and method names inside the correct
和方法名称正确
package and we can navigate to those
包，我们可以导航到那些
directly from the stacktrace
直接从堆栈跟踪
analyzer to show us where that exception
分析器向我们展示该异常情况
was thrown so if you're writing code
被抛出，所以如果您正在编写代码
that's distributed to a large group of
分发给一大群
end-users this is a good way of
最终用户，这是一个很好的方法
protecting your source code and
保护您的源代码并
preventing it from being be compiled
防止其被编译
from the compiled artifact you just have
从您刚刚拥有的编译工件中
to be careful to maintain a copy of that
小心地保留一份副本
ProGuard generated mapping for each of
ProGuard为每个生成的映射
your major releases so that you can go
您的主要版本，以便您可以去
back and analyze any stack traces you
返回并分析您的任何堆栈跟踪
may receive there's also a tool in
可能会收到一个工具
Android called retrace that will allow
Android称为retrace，它将允许
you to do the same thing on the command
您在命令上执行相同的操作
line
线